aw-bc.com 2017-11-11

# Smarthinking Privacy Policy from Pearson

The Smarthinking website is intended to provide tutoring and college-level academic support to students over the age of 13. The Smarthinking Privacy Policy details the commitment of Smarthinking, Inc. to our users' privacy. Please review the following policy to understand how the information you provide Smarthinking, Inc. ("Smarthinking") will be treated.

## Who we are and how to reach us

Smarthinking is the sole provider of this website. You may contact us directly if you have any questions regarding the content and material on this website, or the collection, use, correction or deletion of any personal or non-personal information provided over this website. Please contact us at: 

**Smarthinking, Inc.**  
1919 M St, NW Suite 600  
Washington, DC 20036   
888-430-7429  

##### Usage Eligibility

The Smarthinking service is intended for students over the age of 13. For website activities that request personal information, you agree to provide accurate and current information about yourself. Your membership and/or participation in our website services will be canceled without notice if at any time we discover that you provide false information, or violate any term of this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Usage Use Agreement . If necessary, and in accordance with applicable law, Smarthinking will cooperate with local, state and/or federal authorities to protect its users, parents, partners, affiliates, subsidiaries and operational providers or to prevent unauthorized use of the site.

##### Personal information

The only personal information this website obtains about you is information voluntarily provided by you. You are free to visit Smarthinking; however, if you would like to use the Smarthinking service, you must register. When you register with us, we will request certain personal information including email, phone number, ZIP/postal code, country and, if your school does not provide the Smarthinking service to you, credit card information. Response to our surveys is entirely voluntary and not required for receipt of services.

This information is used by Smarthinking for (1) billing and account purposes; (2) demographic assessments of and provision of services to the user population; (3) empirical research; (4) communication with you; and (5) internal auditing purposes. Only strictly authorized Smarthinking employees have access to this personal information. It may be given to an institutional administrator or a professor if the service is provided through your school or by a textbook publisher. 

In addition to registration information, all electronic text-based conversations between you and Smarthinking’s tutors are digitally captured and stored in Smarthinking’s databases. They may be given to your school administrator, professor, and empirical researchers. Smarthinking may request personal information at other times to better serve your individual needs. As stated above, Smarthinking will not collect any personally identifiable information that you do not voluntarily provide. Smarthinking will not disclose any of your personal information, except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with legal process, (ii) enforce the Registration Agreement or the Terms of Use, (iii) respond to claims that any content on Smarthinking violates the rights of third parties, (iv) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Smarthinking, its users or the public, or (v) respond to the request of your institutional administrators if the service is paid for by them.

Your schools' administrators are within their rights to request access to your personal information and electronic conversations with Smarthinking tutors. Your school, in turn, is subject to the Family Education Rights and Privacy Acts of 1974 (FERPA) restrictions on further disclosure. For further information on FERPA rules and responsibilities, contact your school. 

Smarthinking also reserves the right to replicate written comments about the service sent to its representatives on our website and/or in promotional materials and/or in business development materials, along with your name and institution. Your email address and any personal information besides your name and institution will not be used at any time without your agreement. If you do not want your name to accompany your comments, please state this in your written correspondence with Smarthinking, Inc. and its representatives. 

Smarthinking contains links to other sites and some features of the Smarthinking Service may be offered in conjunction with a partner company. Smarthinking is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites and companies. 

In order to provide partner company features, it may be necessary for either you or Smarthinking to share your voluntarily provided personal information with this company. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.

##### Non-personal Information

Certain non-personal information of visitors is also recorded by the standard operation of Smarthinking’s Internet servers. This information is primarily used to provide visitors to Smarthinking with an enhanced online experience. Information tracked includes the type of browser being used by the visitor, the type of operating system, and the domain name of the visitor's Internet service provider. Smarthinking may disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe the Smarthinking service to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

##### How to add, change, or delete personal information

You have access to your membership profile collected and maintained by our website. We strive to ensure that the information we obtain and use about our members and visitors is accurate. Therefore, you may add, change, or delete personal information on your profile or registration for other activities. Certain information fields are required and cannot be deleted for security purposes or in accordance with various laws. We encourage you to keep us informed about any changes in your membership information and e-mail address. You may change, update or delete certain information in your membership file through the Smarthinking web page: Simply log in to your account, enter the "About Me" page, and change your information as necessary.

##### Use of Cookies

This site requires cookies. Smarthinking uses cookies to establish a session. We do not use cookies for tracking purposes. Cookies do not allow the website to access personal information that you haven't already provided.

##### Our Security Procedures

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of all users. We require our employees to protect the privacy of all information collected over our website. Only employees and supervisors with specific authorization have access to databases containing visitors' personal information. The databases are protected in a secure facility. We have a digital certificate that is signed by a recognized certificate authority. 

Please be advised that once you leave our website, your use of the Internet will be governed by the privacy policies, if any, of the particular website that you are accessing. Smarthinking is not responsible for the content, activities, or privacy practices on the other sites.
